Frances Casement Papers, 1884-1892
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Frances Casement papers
1884-1892
Casement, Frances Jennings, 1841-1920.
MS 30
3 boxes (.75 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Suffragist. The collection of Mrs. Frances Casement, a suffrage leader in Ohio, includes printed materials relating to suffrage and women's rights associations in Ohio and nationally, and miscellaneous records of the Ohio Women's Suffrage Association.
Biographical Note
Frances Casement was an Ohio suffrage leader.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The collection consists of material from purchased from the collection of Mrs. Frances Casement, a suffrage leader in Ohio. Includes periodicals and publications of suffrage and women's rights associations in Ohio and nationally. Also included are the constitution, by-laws, and miscellaneous papers of the Ohio Women's Suffrage Association.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
This collection has not been fully processed and therefore may be difficult to use.
Search Terms
Women's rights--Periodicals; Women--Suffrage-Ohio-History--Sources; Women--Suffrage--United States-History--Sources; Casement, Frances Jennings, 1841-1920.; Ohio Women's Suffrage Association
Container List
- Contents list (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bibliography of Casement Collection in Ohioana Association, Columbus, Ohio, 1940-47 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Newspaper articles and publications about suffrage and women's rights by others, 1851-85, n.d., [detailed list available in Sophia Smith Collection] (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence and photograph, 1898-1901, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Articles about Frances Casement, 1948, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Periodicals collected by F. Casement (Box 2)
  - Eleanor Kirk's Idea, Dec 1892-Jul 1894 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Liberal Thinker, Jan 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The New Era, Jan 1885-Dec 1885 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Our Herald, Feb 1884-Dec 1884 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Queen Isabella Journal, Jan 1890-Dec 1892 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Woman Suffrage (Seattle), Dec 1887 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Working Woman's Journal (formerly Journal of Woman's Work, Dec 1887-May 1892 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Alpha, Dec 1884 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Justitia, Nov 1887-Nov 1888 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The True Republic, Jul 1891-Jul 1892 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Woman's Chronicle, Oct 1889 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Woman's Recorder, Feb-Jun 1892 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Woman's Tribune, Oct 1885-Jul 1886 (Box 3, Folder 6)